cbe.ab.ca 2012-12-31

# Calgary Board of Education - Privacy

home privacy

The Calgary Board of Education (CBE) web site connects you to CBE schools and departments. This web site is maintained to assist you in finding information about the CBE, its schools, programs and services. The Calgary Board of Education is subject to the Alberta _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act_ , and is committed to providing a web site that respects your privacy while you visit us online. This privacy statement summarizes the privacy practices of the Calgary Board of Education with respect to our web site located at www.cbe.ab.ca. 

We do not automatically gather any personal information from you, such as your name, phone number, or e-mail address. This information is obtained only if you supply it voluntarily, usually through contacting us via e-mail or by providing it on an online form. You should review the privacy statement each time you submit personal information on the web site.

Any personal information you do provide is managed according to the _FOIP Act_ __. This means that at the point of collection, you will be informed of the purpose for which your personal information is being collected, the legal authority for collection and the person who can answer your questions about the collection. The Calgary Board of Education does not sell or otherwise distribute any information collected to third parties.

**Information Collected in E-mails and Online Forms**

We treat e-mails with the same respect we treat letters sent to the Calgary Board of Education. We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you. The only personal information collected that is used to identify you is information you give voluntarily. When you submit a question or comment, you may be asked for your name, e-mail address, or other information. This personal information is used to process and respond to your question or comment and is only disclosed to those who need it to answer your question, to the person that your inquiry relates to or to parties legislatively authorized to receive the information.

If you complete an online form and submit it to us through our web site, we use that information for the purposes described on the form. Personal information collected from an online form will be treated in accordance with the privacy protection provisions of the _FOIP Act_.

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**

When you visit the Calgary Board of Education web site, our web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation, security and evaluation of the web site. This information includes:

  * IP address from which you access the CBE web site (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web),
  * type and version of browser used to access our site,
  * date and time you access our site,
  * pages you visit, and
  * if you linked to the Calgary Board of Education web site from another web site, the address of that site.

This information is collected in compliance with the _FOIP Act_. The information is primarily used to help us to assess our services in order to efficiently provide you with the information you require. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small piece of text information that is sent to your browser when you access a web site. Your browser will return this cookie information to the domain where the cookie originated. Cookies may be created when you visit our site. The session cookie we incorporate allows us to determine common paths used by our viewers. This information allows us to streamline navigation to the most requested pages during future upgrades.

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you can refer to the help information in your browser software for information on how to disable cookies. If you wish to delete cookies from your machine, consult your browser’s help files for instructions on how to do so.

**Security**

For site security purposes and to ensure that web services remain available to all users, the district’s computer system uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage to the service we provide. No attempt is made to identify an individual user or their usage patterns except for law enforcement investigations.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

This web site contains links to other sites. The Calgary Board of Education is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices of other web sites. You are encouraged to examine each site’s privacy policy and disclaimers and make your own decisions regarding the accuracy, reliability and correctness of material and information found.

**Contact Information**

Questions about the _FOIP Act_ as it relates to the Calgary Board of Education and concerns regarding privacy or access to information issues should be directed to:

Privacy and Access Officer  
Calgary Board of Education  
Privacy & Access Office, Education Centre   
1221 – 8 St. SW  
Calgary, AB  T2R 0L4  
E-mail: [foip@cbe.ab.ca](mailto:foip@cbe.ab.ca)  
Phone: 403-817-7899  
Fax: 403-777-8028

Content Moderator: [Cathy Evanochko](mailto:CLEvanochko@cbe.ab.ca)   
Web Administrator: [Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@cbe.ab.ca)  
Last Modified: September 24, 2011
